<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<airline>
  <profile name="Air Inter" iata="IT" logo="AirInter" color="Ghostwhite" area="113" CEO="Paul Hébrard" mentality="Moderate" market="Domestic" preferedairport="ORY" onlyfromhome="True">
    <narrative narrative="Air Inter (Lignes Aériennes Intérieures) was a semi-public French domestic airline. Before its merger with Air France, the airline was headquartered in Paray-Vieille-Poste, Essonne. Earlier in its life, it was headquartered in the 1st arrondissement of Paris.
Air Inter was incorporated on 12 November 1954. It operated its first commercial flight between Paris and Strasbourg on 16 March 1958. However, it was 1960 when the airline started regular commercial services.
The company established its operational and engineering base at Paris-Orly Airport, where its flights were concentrated at Orly Ouest, Orly Airport's West Terminal.
Air Inter was founded as a semi-public entity to provide efficient domestic air transport at the lowest cost. Its financial backers included French public and private sector transport businesses in road, rail and air transport, as well as banks.
Fokker 70 in 1996 with Air France and Air Inter logos
Air France and Société Nationale des Chemins de Fer Français (SNCF), the state railway company, were Air Inter's two largest public sector shareholders, each holding 25% in the airline. Union des Transports Aériens (UTA) was its largest private sector investor. UTA initially held a 15% minority stake in Air Inter. UTA subsequently increased its shareholding to 36%, becoming the largest single shareholder.
On 12 January 1990 Air Inter, with UTA and Air France, became part of an enlarged Air France group, which in turn became a subsidiary of Groupe Air France. Air Inter changed to Air Inter Europe following a merger with Air France and UTA. On 1 April 1997, it was absorbed into Air France. On that day, the firm ceased to exist as a legal entity within Groupe Air France."/>
  </profile>

  <info real="True" from="1960" to="1990" />

  <prefereds aircrafts="Aerospatiale N 262,Airbus A300B2,Airbus A300B4,Airbus A320-100,Airbus A320-200,Airbus A321-200,Airbus A330-300,Dassault Mercure,Douglas DC-3,Fokker F27,Fokker F100,Sud Aviation Super Caravelle 12,Vickers Viscount 700"></prefereds>

  <random_routes>
    <routes origin="ORY" destinations="15" minimumsize="Small">
      <countries>
        <country value="113"></country>
      </countries>
    </routes>
  </random_routes>
</airline>
