<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<airline>
  <profile name="O'Connor Airlines" iata="OCM" color="MidnightBlue" area="251" CEO="McGrath Nicol" mentality="Safe" market="Local" preferedairport="MGB">
  <narrative narrative="O'Connor Airlines was around from 1973 until December 14,2007. It was based at Mount Gambier,South Australia. It began as a one plane flight school in 1973. It developed into a freight and apssenger service
  over the years following flying to 18 places around its home state. But it lost its freight contract sometime in the 80s and relaunched itself as a passenger service from Mount Gambier. It began flights to Melbourne and
  Adelaide right away. Around 1990 it began going to Whyalla from Adelaide. In 1998 it bought a route from QanatasLink to serve a route to Mildura,Victoria from Melbourne. In 2006 after the Airlines of South Australia ceased
  it took over its Adelaide to Port Augusta route. In November 2007 the airline went into voluntary administration with debts of 4-5 million Ausitralian dollars. High maintenance and competition were the main blames. It ceased
  on December 14,2007 after not finding a buyer. Many assets were bought by Mount Gambier businessman Adrian de Bruin including the Air Operators Certificate. At the end O'Connor had two BAe Jetstream 32's."/>
</profile>
  <info real="True" from="1973" to="2008" />
  <prefereds aircrafts="BAe Jetstream 31"></prefereds>
   <!--the airliners the airline would start with which isn't on a route earyl (1973) late (2007)-->
	         <airliners>
	    <airliner type="BAe Jetstream 31" early="1" late="2"></airliner>
	     </airliners>
 <routes>
                <route destination1="MGB" destination2="MEL"  />
		<route destination1="MGB" destination2="ADL"  />
		<route destination1="ADL" destination2="WYA" opened="1990" closed="2199"  />
		<route destination1="MEL" destination2="MQL" opened="1998" closed="2199"  />
		<route destination1="ADL" destination2="PUG" opened="2006" closed="2199"   />
	        </routes>




</airline>